<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="./FGDC_Plus.xsl"?><metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
        <origin>Florida Fish and Wildlife Conservation Commission-Fish and Wildlife Research Institute</origin>
        <title>Unified Reef Map v2.0</title>
        <geoform>vector digital data</geoform>
        <pubinfo>
          <pubplace>Saint Petersburg, Fl</pubplace>
          <publish>FWRI</publish>
        </pubinfo>
        <onlink>http://myfwc.com/research/</onlink>
        <onlink>http://ocean.floridamarine.org/IntegratedReefMap/UnifiedReefTract.htm</onlink>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    <descript>
      <abstract>The Unified Reef Map is a regional map of benthic habitats that occur throughout the Florida reef tract. The Unified Reef Map consists of individual maps and monitoring data provided by our numerous partners. The purpose of the Unified Reef Map is to provide a comprehensive view of habitats from Martin County through the Florida Keys to the Dry Tortugas. The Unified Reef Map supports the larger effort to coordinate scientific research and promote a reef-wide approach for protecting Florida’s reef tract. To create the URM, individual maps are integrated, data are edited where overlapping or neighboring maps disagree, and habitat classes are cross-walked to allow comparisons between maps. The URM symbolizes benthic habitats, or bottom types, using the Unified Classification (UC) system. The UC framework allows translation between different classification schemes while retaining the original detailed information provided by our mapping partners. There are five hierarchical UC classes starting at UC Level 0 which represents broad habitat classes and can be consistently translated between individual maps. At the most detailed UC Level 4, benthic habitats are described differently between map providers and may differ throughout the Unified Reef Map. The UC system is also cross-walked to the Coastal and Marine Ecological Classification Standard (CMECS). Un-edited source maps provided by URM map partners are also available. The Unified Reef Map is a living map and will be updated as new data become available. Version 2.0 released January 2017. For more information visit: http://ocean.floridamarine.org/IntegratedReefMap/UnifiedReefTract.htm</abstract>
      <purpose>The purpose of the Unified Reef Map is to provide a comprehensive view of habitats from Martin County through the Florida Keys to the Dry Tortugas. The Unified Reef Map supports the larger effort to coordinate scientific research and promote a reef-wide approach for protecting Florida’s reef tract.</purpose>
      <supplinf>Prior to July 1, 2004, the Fish and Wildlife Research Institute (FWRI) was known as the Florida Marine Research Institute (FMRI). The institute name has not been changed in historical data sets or references to work completed by the Florida Marine Research Institute. The institute name has been changed in references to ongoing research, new research, and contact information.</supplinf>
    </descript>
    <status>
      <progress>Complete</progress>
      <update>Continually</update>
    </status>
    <spdom>
      <bounding>
        <westbc>-83.102217</westbc>
        <eastbc>-80.052258</eastbc>
        <northbc>26.021202</northbc>
        <southbc>24.316294</southbc>
      </bounding>
    </spdom>
    <keywords>
      <theme>
        <themekt>ISO 19115 Topic Categories</themekt>
        <themekey>oceans</themekey>
        <themekey>environment</themekey>
        <themekey>inlandWaters</themekey>
        <themekey>biota</themekey>
      </theme>
      <theme>
        <themekt>FWRItheme</themekt>
        <themekey>mapping</themekey>
        <themekey>coastal</themekey>
        <themekey>ecology</themekey>
        <themekey>corals (reefs</themekey>
        <themekey>habitat (rivers</themekey>
        <themekey>hard bottom)</themekey>
        <themekey>marine</themekey>
        <themekey>marine vegetation (mangroves</themekey>
        <themekey>benthic</themekey>
        <themekey>etc.)</themekey>
        <themekey>sea oats)</themekey>
        <themekey>seagrasses</themekey>
        <themekey>estuaries</themekey>
        <themekey>GIS</themekey>
        <themekey>seaweeds</themekey>
      </theme>
      <theme>
        <themekt>EPA GIS Keyword Thesaurus</themekt>
        <themekey>Ecology</themekey>
      </theme>
      <theme>
        <themekt>ISO 19115 Topic Category</themekt>
        <themekey>biota</themekey>
        <themekey>oceans</themekey>
        <themekey>environment</themekey>
      </theme>
      <place>
        <placekt>Florida Counties</placekt>
        <placekey>Monroe</placekey>
        <placekey>Dade</placekey>
      </place>
      <place>
        <placekt>Water Management Districts</placekt>
        <placekey>South Florida Water Management District</placekey>
      </place>
      <place>
        <placekt>FWC Region</placekt>
        <placekey>FWC Region-South</placekey>
      </place>
      <place>
        <placekt>Florida Waterbodies</placekt>
        <placekey>Florida Bay</placekey>
        <placekey>Gulf of Mexico</placekey>
        <placekey>Atlantic Ocean</placekey>
      </place>
      <place>
        <placekt>FWRIplace</placekt>
        <placekey>south Florida</placekey>
        <placekey>Florida Bay</placekey>
        <placekey>Florida Keys National Marine Sanctuary</placekey>
        <placekey>Florida</placekey>
        <placekey>Florida Keys</placekey>
      </place>
    </keywords>
    <accconst>Available without restriction. All data must be verified by Principal Investigator or Group Database Analyst prior to release. It is strongly recommended that this data is directly acquired from FWC and not indirectly through other sources which may have changed the data in some way. FWC makes no claims as to the data's suitability for other purposes.</accconst>
    <useconst>Acknowledgement of the FWC-FWRI (Florida Fish and Wildlife Conservation Commission-Fish and Wildlife Research Institute) as the data source would be appreciated in any products developed from these data, and such acknowledgment as is standard for citation and legal practices for data source is expected by users of this data. Please cite the original metadata when using portions of the record to create a similar record of slightly altered data, such as reprojection. If any data are modified or adjusted, please share the edited information with FWC. Users should be aware that comparison with other data sets for the same area from other time periods may be inaccurate due to inconsistencies resulting from changes in mapping conventions, data collection, and computer processes over time. FWC shall not be liable for improper or incorrect use of this data. These data are not legal documents and are not to be used as such. This is not a survey data set and should not be utilized as such. These data are not to be used for navigation.</useconst>
    <ptcontac>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>Florida Fish and Wildlife Conservation Commission-Fish and Wildlife Research Institute</cntorg>
          <cntper>GISLibrarian@MyFWC.com</cntper>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype>
          <address>Fish and Wildlife Research Institute 100 Eighth Avenue Southeast</address>
          <city>St. Petersburg</city>
          <state>FL</state>
          <postal>33701</postal>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>727-896-8626</cntvoice>
      </cntinfo>
    </ptcontac>
    <datacred>This project was made possible by the contribution of data and expertise from partners and funded by NOAA's Office of Ocean and Coastal Resource Management in partnership with the Florida Department of Environmental Protection's Coastal Management Program.  See project metadata for individual source map credits.</datacred>
    <secinfo>
      <sechandl>Available without restriction</sechandl>
    </secinfo>
    <native>Microsoft Windows 7 Version 6.1 (Build 7601) Service Pack 1; Esri ArcGIS 10.3.1.4959</native>
  </idinfo>
  <dataqual>
    <attracc>
      <attraccr>All entities and attributes have been identified. A comparison between the 1:24,000-scale maps of the compiled data and the original delineated photos to determine the positional accuracy of polygonal shapes and attributes was part of the QC process (see process step).</attraccr>
    </attracc>
    <logic>The data were verified for logical consistency between field values.</logic>
    <complete>This is a versioned product that will be continually updated.</complete>
    <posacc>
      <horizpa>
        <horizpar>All spatial edits were performed using the best available imagery, in situ observation data, high resolution bathymetric data and earlier benthic maps. See source map metadata for positional accuracy reports specific to source data. Individual source map feature classes can be cross-referenced using the Source field.</horizpar>
      </horizpa>
    </posacc>
    <lineage>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>FWC FWRI</origin>
            <title>Unified Florida Patch Reef Map_V14 2016</title>
            <othercit>The Unified Patch Reef Map was created by extracting patch reef features from several maps throughout the Keys including NOAA, Nova Southeastern University (NSU), National Park Service (NPS), and previous FWC mapping efforts resulting in a GIS layer consisting of 14,196 patch reefs identified using the best available imagery and a consistent minimum mapping unit (MMU=150sqm) and digitizing scale (1:3,000) throughout the Florida Keys Reef Tract. Where the Unified Patch Reef Map layer intersected the Unified Florida Reef Tract Map, numerous features were edited and updated using newer, higher resolution imagery. As a result, there will be considerable differences between the Unified Florida Reef Tract Map v1.3 and the Unified Florida Reef Tract Map v2.0.</othercit>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <srcscale>0</srcscale>
        <typesrc>None</typesrc>
        <srccitea>Unified Florida Patch Reef Map_V14 2016</srccitea>
      </srcinfo>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>FWC/National Park Service</origin>
            <title>Benthic Habitats Biscayne Bay 2005 - 2008 (Biscayne Bay aquatic preserve - northern portion)</title>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <srcscale>0</srcscale>
        <typesrc>None</typesrc>
        <srccitea>Benthic Habitats Biscayne Bay 2005 - 2008 (Biscayne Bay aquatic preserve - northern portion)</srccitea>
      </srcinfo>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>Nova Southeastern University Oceanographic Center</origin>
            <pubdate>20040101</pubdate>
            <title>Benthic Habitats Broward County Florida 2004</title>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <srcscale>0</srcscale>
        <typesrc>None</typesrc>
        <srccitea>Benthic Habitats Broward County Florida 2004</srccitea>
      </srcinfo>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>Florida Fish and Wildlife Conservation Commission-Fish and Wildlife Research Institute</origin>
            <pubdate>20050101</pubdate>
            <title>Benthic Habitats Florida Bay 2004</title>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <srcscale>0</srcscale>
        <typesrc>None</typesrc>
        <srccitea>Benthic Habitats Florida Bay 2004</srccitea>
      </srcinfo>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>Nova Southeastern University Oceanographic Center</origin>
            <pubdate>20090101</pubdate>
            <title>Benthic Habitats North Miami-Dade Florida 2009</title>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <srcscale>0</srcscale>
        <typesrc>None</typesrc>
        <srccitea>Benthic Habitats North Miami-Dade Florida 2009</srccitea>
      </srcinfo>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>FWC</origin>
            <title>North Keys/Backcountry FWC</title>
            <pubinfo>
              <publish>FWC FWRI</publish>
            </pubinfo>
            <othercit>This is a final draft of the North Keys/Backcountry FWC benthic map. This map has not been assessed for acccuracy. Benthic type was interpreted using the best available satellite and aerial imagery, LiDAR data, and in situ observations where available. WorldView-2 and Geo-Eye satellite imagery and aerial photography were also used to aid in classification. Polygons were heads up digitized into a Geodatabase using ArcMap 10.2.</othercit>
            <onlink>GeoEye-1 satellite Imagery</onlink>
            <onlink>WorldView-2 satellite Imagery</onlink>
            <onlink>NOAA LiDAR 2012</onlink>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <srcscale>0</srcscale>
        <typesrc>None</typesrc>
        <srccitea>North Keys/Backcountry FWC</srccitea>
      </srcinfo>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>FWC</origin>
            <title>Benthic Habitats South Florida 1991 - 2001</title>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <srcscale>50000</srcscale>
        <typesrc>None</typesrc>
        <srccitea>Benthic Habitats South Florida 1991 - 2001</srccitea>
        <srccontr>Used to fill in a few minor data gaps</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>FWC</origin>
            <title>Boca Grande Channel</title>
            <pubinfo>
              <publish>FWC FWRI</publish>
            </pubinfo>
            <othercit>This is a final draft of the Boca Grande Channel benthic map. Accuracy Assessment is planned to be completed next year. Benthic type was interpreted using side-scan sonar and LiDAR reflectance and relative depth data. WorldView-2 satellite imagery and aerial photography were also used to aid in classification. Polygons were heads up digitized into a Geodatabase using ArcMap 10.2. In situ observations were used to inform photo interpretation.</othercit>
            <onlink>WorldView-2 satellite Imagery</onlink>
            <onlink>FWC Side-scan sonar 2012 and 2013</onlink>
            <onlink>NOAA LiDAR 2012</onlink>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <srcscale>0</srcscale>
        <typesrc>None</typesrc>
        <srccitea>Boca Grande Channel</srccitea>
      </srcinfo>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>Nova Southeastern University Oceanographic Center</origin>
            <title>Southeast Florida Benthic Habitat Update 2015</title>
            <othercit>This shapefile is a combination of the most recent SE FL benthic habitat maps. The nearshore has been updated according to Walker and Klug 2014 (Hillsboro inlet to Fowey Rocks) and Cumming 2017 (Lake Worth inlet to Boynton inlet) combined with all previous mapping efforts. Cumming combined all hardbottom mapping from 2000 to present to obtain the total nearshore hardbottom extent. This habitat is variably exposed depending on temporal shifting sediment, beach nourishments, and large storm events. The Ecosystem regions were defiend in Walker 2012 and Walker and Gilliam 2013.The SE FL nearshore benthic habitats were mapped using the same combined technique approach as described in Walker, Riegl, and Dodge (2008). Polygons were created by outlining and defining the features at a 1:1,000 scale and minimum mapping unit of 0.1 ha within recent aerial photography and high resolution bathymetric survey data. Southeast Florida benthic habitat maps were produced by delineating seafloor features evident in multiple datasets including the GMR Aerial Surveys, Inc. dba Photo Scienceimagery collected for this purpose on March 8, 2013, 2008 Broward lidar, and 2009 NOAA bathymetry. This dataset built upon previous regional mapping efforts by Dr. Brian Walker at Nova Southeastern University. The habitats were classified according to established NOAA guidelines in coordination with the NOS Coral Mapping Program and use a similar classification scheme when possible.</othercit>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <srcscale>0</srcscale>
        <typesrc>None</typesrc>
        <srccitea>Southeast Florida Benthic Habitat Update 2015</srccitea>
      </srcinfo>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>Coastal Planning &amp; Engineering, Inc.</origin>
            <pubdate>20110101</pubdate>
            <title>Benthic Habitats Marquesas-Quicksands Florida 2006</title>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <srcscale>0</srcscale>
        <typesrc>None</typesrc>
        <srccitea>Benthic Habitats Marquesas-Quicksands Florida 2006</srccitea>
      </srcinfo>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>National Park Service</origin>
            <title>Biscayne National Park 2005 - 2013</title>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <srcscale>0</srcscale>
        <typesrc>None</typesrc>
        <srccitea>Biscayne National Park 2005 - 2013</srccitea>
      </srcinfo>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>FWC</origin>
            <title>Hawk Channel</title>
            <pubinfo>
              <publish>FWC FWRI</publish>
            </pubinfo>
            <othercit>This is a final draft of the Hawk Channel benthic map. Accuracy Assessment is planned to be completed next year. Benthic type was interpreted using side-scan sonar and LiDAR reflectance and relative depth data. WorldView-2 satellite imagery and aerial photography were also used to aid in classification. Polygons were heads up digitized into a Geodatabase using ArcMap 10.2. In situ observations were used to inform photo interpretation.</othercit>
            <onlink>WorldView-2 Imagery 9/2010, 7/2011, 10/2012, 1/2013, 7/2013</onlink>
            <onlink>FWC Side-scan sonar 2012 and 2013</onlink>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <srcscale>0</srcscale>
        <typesrc>None</typesrc>
        <srccitea>Hawk Channel</srccitea>
      </srcinfo>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>NOAA and Miles Anderson, Analytical Laboratories of Hawaii and Richard Eastlake, Photo Science Inc., NOAA NOS NCCOS, CCMA</origin>
            <pubdate>20120101</pubdate>
            <title>Benthic Habitats of Florida Keys Derived From IKONOS satellite imagery</title>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <srcscale>0</srcscale>
        <typesrc>None</typesrc>
        <srccitea>Benthic Habitats of Florida Keys Derived From IKONOS satellite imagery</srccitea>
      </srcinfo>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>Nova Southeastern University Oceanographic Center</origin>
            <title>Benthic Habitats Offshore Palm Beach County Florida 2002</title>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <srcscale>0</srcscale>
        <typesrc>None</typesrc>
        <srccitea>Benthic Habitats Offshore Palm Beach County Florida 2002</srccitea>
      </srcinfo>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>National Park Service</origin>
            <title>Benthic Habitats Dry Tortugas Florida 2010</title>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <srcscale>0</srcscale>
        <typesrc>None</typesrc>
        <srccitea>Benthic Habitats Dry Tortugas Florida 2010</srccitea>
      </srcinfo>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>National Park Service, Avineon</origin>
            <title>Benthic Habitat East Biscayne National Park Florida 2008</title>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <srcscale>0</srcscale>
        <typesrc>None</typesrc>
        <srccitea>Benthic Habitat East Biscayne National Park Florida 2008</srccitea>
      </srcinfo>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>Version 1.0 published</procdesc>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>Version 2.0 – Data additions : Unified Florida Patch Reef Map and the Southeast Florida Benthic Habitat Update. Southeast Florida Benthic Habitat data was edited to not overwrite NPS dataset overlap . Data surrounding these areas were edited at seams to match updates. . Data intersected by these additions were edited for geometry and classification.</procdesc>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>Version 1.3 - Data addition: Northern Marquesas and Backcountry Areas. Data surrounding these areas were edited at seams to match updates and map topology errors throughout the map were corrected.</procdesc>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>Version 1.2 - Data addition: Hawk Channel. Boca Grande Channel. Data surrounding these areas were edited at seams to match updates.</procdesc>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>Reclassification and geometry editing procedures are detailed in accompanying report</procdesc>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>Version 1.1 - Data addition: Biscayne Bay Aquatic Preserve. Seams integrated with Biscayne Bay NPS data and SE Florida Data (at inlets). Edits have not yet be accuracy assessed. Zone information added for SE Florida and Marquesas.</procdesc>
      </procstep>
    </lineage>
  </dataqual>
  <spdoinfo>
    <direct>Vector</direct>
    <ptvctinf>
      <sdtsterm>
        <sdtstype>GT-polygon composed of chains</sdtstype>
        <ptvctcnt>49669</ptvctcnt>
      </sdtsterm>
    </ptvctinf>
  </spdoinfo>
  <spref>
    <horizsys>
      <planar>
        <mapproj>
          <mapprojn>WGS 1984 Web Mercator Auxiliary Sphere</mapprojn>
          <mapprojp>
            <otherprj>PROJCS["WGS_1984_Web_Mercator_Auxiliary_Sphere",GEOGCS["GCS_WGS_1984",DATUM["D_WGS_1984",SPHEROID["WGS_1984",6378137.0,298.257223563]],PRIMEM["Greenwich",0.0],UNIT["Degree",0.0174532925199433]],PROJECTION["Mercator_Auxiliary_Sphere"],PARAMETER["False_Easting",0.0],PARAMETER["False_Northing",0.0],PARAMETER["Central_Meridian",0.0],PARAMETER["Standard_Parallel_1",0.0],PARAMETER["Auxiliary_Sphere_Type",0.0],UNIT["Meter",1.0],AUTHORITY["EPSG",3857]]</otherprj>
          </mapprojp>
        </mapproj>
        <planci>
          <plance>coordinate pair</plance>
          <coordrep>
            <absres>0.0001</absres>
            <ordres>0.0001</ordres>
          </coordrep>
          <plandu>meter</plandu>
        </planci>
      </planar>
      <geodetic>
        <horizdn>D WGS 1984</horizdn>
        <ellips>WGS 1984</ellips>
        <semiaxis>6378137.0</semiaxis>
        <denflat>298.257223563</denflat>
      </geodetic>
    </horizsys>
  </spref>
  <eainfo xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions" xmlns:xdt="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-datatypes">
    <detailed>
      <enttyp>
        <enttypl>UnifiedReefMap</enttypl>
        <enttypds>Producer defined</enttypds>
      </enttyp>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>ClassLv4</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Unified Classification Level 4. This is the most detailed thematic classification level.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>FWC</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Shape_Length</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Length of feature in internal units.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Esri</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Positive real numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>OBJECTID</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Internal feature number.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Esri</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Sequential unique whole numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>BioCoverDe</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Biological Cover Detail - This field retains the original source data classification values</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Orginal source layer</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>GeoformDet</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Geoform Detail: This field retains the original source data classification values</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Orginal source layer</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Zone_</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Reef Zone</attrdef>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Source</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Original mapping project reference</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>FWC</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>ClassLv3</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Unified Classification Level 3</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>FWC</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>CMECS_Bio</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>CMECS Biological Cover cross-walk</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>FWC</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>BioCover</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Biological Cover - This field retains the original source data classification values</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Orginal source layer</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Shape_Area</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Area of feature in internal units squared.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Esri</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Positive real numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>ClassLv0</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Unified Classification Level 0. This is the coarsest (most general) thematic level.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>FWC</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>PercentBio</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Percent Biological Cover - This field retains the original source data classification values</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Orginal source layer</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>GeoForm</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>GeoForm - This field retains the original source data classification values</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Orginal source layer</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>GeoformD_1</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>OBJECTID_1</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Internal feature number.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Esri</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Sequential unique whole numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>ClassLv2</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Unified Classification Level 2</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>FWC</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>CMECS_Geo</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>CMECS Geoform cross-walk</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>FWC</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Shape</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Feature geometry.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Esri</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Coordinates defining the features.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Shape_Leng</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Acres</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>ClassLv1</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Unified Classification Level 1</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>FWC</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>PercentCor</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Percent Coral Cover - No distinction is made between soft and stony coral. This field retains the original source data classification values</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Orginal source layer</attrdefs>
      </attr>
    </detailed>
    <overview>
      <eaover>As specified in the attribute definitions, some attribute fields represent the original source data classification information. Not all features will have information for these original source data fields.</eaover>
    </overview>
  </eainfo>
  <distinfo>
    <distrib>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>FWC-FWRI (Florida Fish and Wildlife Conservation Commission-Fish and Wildlife Research Institute)</cntorg>
          <cntper>GISLibrarian</cntper>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntpos>GIS Data Librarian</cntpos>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype>
          <address>Fish and Wildlife Research Institute 100 Eighth Avenue Southeast</address>
          <city>St. Petersburg</city>
          <state>Florida</state>
          <postal>33701</postal>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>727-896-8626</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>727-893-1679</cntfax>
        <cntemail>GISLibrarian@MyFWC.com</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </distrib>
    <distliab>This data set is in the public domain, and the recipient may not assert any proprietary rights thereto nor represent it to anyone as other than a FWC-FWRI produced data set; it is provided "as-is" without warranty of any kind, including, but not limited to, the implied warranties of merchantability and fitness for a particular purpose. The user assumes all responsibility for the accuracy and suitability of this data set for a specific application. In no event will the staff of the Fish and Wildlife Research Institute be liable for any damages, including lost profits, lost savings, or other incidental or consequential damages arising from the use of or the inability to use this data set.</distliab>
    <stdorder>
      <digform>
        <digtinfo>
          <formname>SHP</formname>
        </digtinfo>
      </digform>
      <fees>None. However, persons or organizations requesting information must provide transfer media if FTP is not available and must pay express shipping costs if express shipping is required.</fees>
      <ordering>Contact GIS Librarian by e-mail, telephone, or letter explaining which products are needed and providing a brief description of how the products will be used. Also, provide name and address of the person or organization requesting the products.</ordering>
      <turnarnd>Usually within 10 business days, although, complex requests may take longer</turnarnd>
    </stdorder>
  </distinfo>
  <metainfo>
    <metd>20170120</metd>
    <metrd>20071115</metrd>
    <metc>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>FWC-FWRI (Florida Fish and Wildlife Conservation Commission-Fish and Wildlife Research Institute)</cntorg>
          <cntper>GISLibrarian</cntper>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntpos>GIS Data Librarian</cntpos>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype>
          <address>Fish and Wildlife Research Institute 100 Eighth Avenue Southeast</address>
          <city>St. Petersburg</city>
          <state>Florida</state>
          <postal>33701</postal>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>727-896-8626</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>727-893-1679</cntfax>
        <cntemail>GISLibrarian@MyFWC.com</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </metc>
    <metstdn>FGDC Content Standard for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
    <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
    <mettc>local time</mettc>
    <metac>No restrictions on metadata.</metac>
    <metuc>Metadata must be distributed with the data set.</metuc>
    <metsi>
      <metscs>FWRI-MC</metscs>
      <metshd>Metadata must be distributed with the data set.</metshd>
    </metsi>
  </metainfo>
</metadata>